Andrew Ellul



Lerchenauer Strasse 142, 80935 Munich, Germany



+49 152 5541 5630



andrew.t.ellul@gmail.com



https://github.com/interimblue





Profile

A TUM M.Sc Informatik student and an experienced Lead IT Consultant with several years' experience in software development, software architecture and functional specification design. University of Manchester graduate (1st Class B.Sc (Hons) Computer Science) with international experience in business technology within the UK banking sector and the German automotive industry. Key competencies are data science, social network analysis, software development, entrepreneurship, technology product development, IT strategy, functional specification of business facing IT, Scrum & Agile frameworks, enterprise systems. Skilled in Java, Python, Javascript, SQL and NoSQL. Fluent in English, German and Maltese. Certified Scrum Product Owner.



Education

10/2019 - Present

Technische Universität München, M.Sc. Informatik

- Major: Machine Learning and Analytics, Natural Language Processing, Deep Learning
- Minors: Algorithms, Distributed Systems

09/2011 - 06/2015

The University of Manchester, B.Sc. (Hons) Computer Science

- Overall Grade: 1st Class Honours
- Bachelor Thesis (Distinction): "A Tool for Exploring Centrality Sensitivity"
 - A sociological tool to detect important nodes in a social network and analyse the probability and scale of network disruptions based on fluctuating connections
- PASS Leader: Tutored and mentored younger students
- Computer Science Society Treasurer: Managed finances, organised events
- **Scout Leader:** Set up and helped run a local scout group for young adolescents where we helped teach leadership and teamwork skills



Experience

09/2016 - 09/2019

Machine Learning Working Student / Intern, Amazon AWS, Munich

 Researching and developing experimental AI pipelines to understand customers' optimal usage patterns of AWS services and serve automated suggestions for architectural improvements

09/2016 - 09/2019

Lead IT Consultant, Capgemini, Berlin

05/2019 – 09/2019

Al Consultant (Computer Vision) – Researching and developing Proof of Concepts for computer vision use cases in manufacturing.

11/2017 - 05/2019

Lead IT Consultant - Product owner and chief functional designer for several digital platforms at Volkswagen Financial Services:

- Design of System Architecture, UML, Sequence Diagrams,
- Researching technology/tools for implementation ReactJs, NodeJs, Java 8, AWS

09/2016 - 10/2017

IT Consultant - Functional architect for algorithm-based statistical manufacturing systems at BMW

- Development of features in Java EE
- · Requirements gathering, documentation and clarification
- Performing code-reviews and developing bug fixes
- Setup of CI infrastructure and test pipelines
- Development of proof of concepts in Java and Javascript.

01/2016 - 07/2016

Software Engineer (Backend), Signavio GmbH, Berlin

• Java 8, NoSQL, MongoDb, SQL, Hibernate, SaaS, Javascript, Petrinets, Process Mininig, BPMN,

06/2014 - 09/2014

Technology Developer (Intern), Goldman Sachs, London

- Software Engineer Intern for Equity One-Delta Trading Support: Developed a RESTful data reference system using a proprietary programming language (SLANG) for Trading apps
- Developed a working knowledge of financial instruments & large interconnected trading systems. Developed software to support the equity trading desk

07/2013 - 06/2014

Technology Analyst (Intern), J. P. Morgan Chase, Bournemouth

- Business Analyst: Managed and led the technical integration of multiple payment processing systems as part of a team tasked with rolling out a strategic middle-office application to the entire Investment Bank
- Personally initiated, developed and presented a project that visually mapped the communication pathways within our system using D3JS and Java Servlets in order to identify and resolve communication bottlenecks.
- Solely managed the proof-of-concept phase of each system integration project and consequently worked with technology teams and executives in New York, London, Hong Kong and Tokyo



Awards

10/2015 Undergraduate Awards, Highly Commended, Dublin

Submitted bachelor thesis titled "A Tool For Exploring Centrality Sensitivity" which ranked amongst the top submissions in the computer science category, internationally. Won a seat at the Undergraduate Awards international conference in Dublin aimed at

addressing current world issues

2013 Manchester Leadership Programme – Manchester Leadership Award



Skills & Interests

Data Science Pytorch, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Graph and

Network Science

Programming Python, Java 8, Graph Algorithms, Sql, Hibernate, Maven, MVC Architecture, Unix/Bash

scripting, Git, OO Design, TDD, Oracle DB, MongoDB,

Methodologies/Tools: Scrum Product Ownership, Agile, JIRA, Confluence, Kanban, Gantt Charts,

Languages English (Native), German (Fluent), Maltese (Fluent), French (Basic)

Interests Bouldering, mountain hiking, guitar, running psychology & philosophy literature



Volunteering / Positions of Responsibility

2019	Event organiser, TEDxTUM
2014	Maths Tutor, TutorTrust Manchester
2012 / 2013	Committee Treasurer, Computer Science Society
2012 / 2013	Assistant Scout Leader, Scout Association, Manchester
2011	Officer Cadet, The Royal Navy, Manchester
2005 - 2011	Various Roles, Scout Association, Malta